Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
- BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS, 1916-1980; Series VII; 1' (2 boxes)
  Also represented is a plaque installed in Sprague Memorial Hall, Yale University, in 1976 by the National Music Council Bicentennial Committee. The correspondence, text of the plaque, and newspaper articles covering this occasion are found in Folder 332.
  - Personal Recollections (Box 19, Folder 319)
    - A. Erfurth: Remembrances of Paul Hindemith, in Stuttgarter Zeitung 14 Nov 1970, 1931
    - R. P. Spoettle: memo given to P. Nelson at alumni meeting in New York, pre-1934
    - J. Moran Myer - letter to her father, 19 Oct 1940
    - G. Lam: description of his first composition class 30 Sept, reported in letter to L. Noss 20 Feb 1964, 1941
    - J. Rush Crocker: report from "Composition for Non-Majors" spring semester in letter to L. Noss 13 Aug 1973, 1949
    - American Choral Review Vol. VI No. 3 - Henry Kaufmann, Bernhard Heiden, Kurt Stone, Arthur Mendel, Apr 1964
    - E. J. O'Meara: Paul Hindemith and his Use of the Yale Music Library, Nov 1964
    - E. Straley: tribute to Paul Hindemith in letter to B. Shepard, 20 May 1965
    - M. Stomne Selden: anecdotes, 24 May 1965
    - J. Sykes: in letter to B. Shepard, 5 Nov 1965
    - A. Rebner: My Pupil Paul Hindemith, in Jahrbuch I/71 - original and translation, 1965
    - M. Rieple: Meetings with Paul Hindemith, in Jahrbuch I/71 - translation only, 1965
    - S. Kind: Hindemith as a Teacher in Berlin, in Music Journal, Mar 1966
    - F. Schramm: Reminiscences of an Old Frankfurter - privately printed pamphlet with excerpts about Paul Hindemith translated, 1971
    - E. Soule: letter to L. Noss, 22 May 1972
    - F. Lewin, in letter to B. Shepard 27 Mar 1965, undated
    - G. Kubler: inaccurate World War I story "told by Paul Hindemith", undated
  - Personal Recollections (Box 19, Folder 320)
    - K. Liepmann: account of Paul Hindemith's first appearance at Yale, 27 Feb 1938
    - M. Landsberger: Reminiscence of Paul Hindemith in Buffalo, 1940
    - H. Russell: Meeting Paul Hindemith at the Sloane Physics Laboratory, Nov 1944
    - M. Barker Nelson: Personal reminiscences, 1948-50
    - M. Bozyan - farewell party; Paul Hindemith and Children, 2 May 1953
    - M. Bartholomew - letters to B. Shepard: 18 Feb 1964; 12 Sept 1964; 16 Oct 1964; 4 May 1967, with 8 p. of recollections in typescript, 1964-67
    - D. Buttolph, 2 May 1965
    - H. Straumann: Remembrances of Hindemith's Zurich Period - Jahrbuch I/71, 1971
    - C. Fraker: Recollections, 11 June 1973
    - H. Fromm: essay excerpted from Seven Pockets - Dorrance., 1977
    - M. Powell, Profile of, in New Yorker, 25 May 1987
  - The Legacy of Paul Hindemith - Canadian Broadcasting Company, with original transcripts and edited versions by L. Noss, 12 Jan 1964 (Box 19, Folder 321)
    - Interview with Graham George
    - Interview with Lucas Foss
    - Interview with Violet Archer
  - The Legacy of Paul Hindemith - Canadian Broadcasting Company, with original transcripts and edited versions by L. Noss, 12 Jan 1964 (Box 19, Folder 322)
    - Interview with Arnold Walter
    - Interview with Helmut Blume
  - Published Biographical Data (Box 19, Folder 323)
    - H. Blumenthal: entry on Paul Hindemith for 1973-74 ed. International Cyclopedia of Music and Musicians
    - A. Briner: addenda to Paul Hindemith biography in Riemann's Lexikon supplement 1971 untranslated
    - P. Cahn: Hindemith's School Years in Frankfurt, in Jahrbuch 1I/72
    - Paul Hindemith: autobiographical sketch, in Neue Musik-Zeitung - Vol. 20, 1922
    - G. Thalheimer-Lowe (Mrs. John): interviews in New Haven Register 23 Aug 1973 & 27 Aug 1978
    - C. R. Thoburn, Crawford R.: Hindemith at Wells College two photocopies of two-part article in Wells Express, December 1966 and January 1967
    - H. Weber: Paul Hindemith's First Important Piano Interpreter - article about Emma Lübbecke-Job, in Jahrbuch III/73
    - J. Wulf: Attacks on Paul Hindemith in German press ca. 1930, in Musik im Dritten Reich (1963) - translations only
  - Miscellaneous Printed Notices (Box 19, Folder 323)
    - Paul Hindemith professional card, in Melos, 1922
    - Yale Daily News re: Paul Hindemith election to National Institute, 1947
    - New Haven Federation of Musicians notice of Paul Hindemith as a new member, March 1950
    - Notice of oil furnace company in Frankfurt - Öhlfueuerungsbau Hindemith KG, 1958
    - New York Times: Paul Hindemith made honorary member of New York Philharmonic Orchestra, 29 Feb 1960
    - Paul Hindemith Conducts Yale University Collegium card, 19 Feb 1960
    - New Haven Federation of Musicians notice of Paul Hindemith's death, Jan 1964
    - Program of 70th birthday exhibition: Paul Hindemith. Emigration und Rückkehr nach Europa, in Frankfurt; contains Paul Hindemith's address in Wuppertal 4 June 1955 and extensive bibliography, Nov-Dec 1965
    - Invitation and program: Paul Hindemith/Emigration und Rückkehr nach Europa, in Zurich, 17 Feb 1966
    - Frankfurter Wochenschau, p. 9 contains notice of Kuhhirtenturm, medieval tower where Paul Hindemith lived from 1923 to 1925, 16-31 Mar 1980
  - Published Biographical Data (Box 19, Folder 324)
    - Biographical notes from Boston Symphony Orchestra program, 25-26 Feb 1938
    - Page from Robert French's Annual Report to the President describing Paul Hindemith's lecture in Jonathan Edwards College, 1940?
    - E. Preussner: Musica est ars et scientia - Hindemith in Salzburg und in Wien, in unidentified Viennese newspaper, 1948
    - Biographical sketch in Cincinnati Orchestra program, 9-10 Dec 1950
    - H. L. Schilling: Hindemith on the Rostrum (as teacher in Zurich), in Melos 22/11, 1955
    - E. Preussner: Paul Hindemith entry in Musik in Geschichte und Gegenwart in part 4) of original + translation, 1957
    - F. K. Prieberg: Paul Hindemith entry in Lexikon der neuen Musik - original only, 1958
    - O. Daniel: Hindemith called the Leonardo da Vinci of music, giving performance data for 1959-60 season - BMI publicity
    - Stevenson cartoon in New Yorker - original is in oversize Box 43, 26 Dec 1959
    - H. Straumann: Hindemith's Appointment to the University of Zurich, in Schweizerische Musikzeitung - comprising printed version, photocopy of typescript, and L. Noss translation, Dec 1966
    - A. Briner: Paul Hindemith and Winterthur, in Melos, Apr 1969
    - K. Viedebandtt: Documents on Exile Literature Return to Frankfurt, in Der Tagespiel 7 Jan, reprinted in The German Tribune, 3 Feb 1972
    - P. Hayworth: note on Furtwängler in conversations with Otto Klemperer. Gollancz, 1973
    - G. Emerson: two interviews with Szymon Goldberg, 20 Aug & 27 Aug 1978
    - Deutscher Musikwettbewerb Repertoire - Liste zur Ausschreibung DMW, 1978
    - G. Skelton: The Man Behind the Music, introduction, undated
    - Various Record Jacket Notes, undated
    - A. Cohn: comments from Decca recording, undated
    - H. Schramm: comments from Candide recording, undated
    - K. Schumann: comments from Helidor recording, undated
    - R. Evett: comments from GSC recording, undated
  - Unpublished Biographical Data (Box 19, Folder 325)
    - J. Silberstein: comments made to L. Noss mostly about Rudolph Hindemith, violoncellist, 20 Sept 1978
    - When & Where Data, compiled by L. Noss omitting all references to compositions
    - Notes from Schott-Paul Hindemith files, compiled by L. Noss, Oct 1977
    - Announcement of Paul Hindemith appointment as a new Fellow of Jonathan Edwards College; autographed card acknowledging reappointment as Fellow, (?1945/48/51?)
    - W. Strecker-G. Havemann, chief of Reichsmusikkammer, Berlin - a draft of a letter, 9 Mar 1935
    - Biographical notes on Theodor Wiesengrund-Adorno
    - Reply to request by L. Noss for information on studying with Paul Hindemith. Includes full data on admission requirements to the Berlin Hochschule in 1933
    - Anon. parody on "The Night Before Christmas" read at Yale School of Music Christmas party, December 1943 or 1944
    - L. Noss notes in file: Paul Hindemith's vists to Yale in spring of 1940 were funded in part by the Carl Schurz Foundation
    - L. Noss notes in file: Paul Hindemith's royalties, held by US Alien Property Custodian, were released in 1951
  - From Jahrbuch II/72: Paul Hindemith's Letters to the Ronnefeldt family, 1916-1922 (Box 19, Folder 326)
    Paul Hindemith describes in detail his army life, musical activities, and attitudes toward other musicians.
    Photocopy [translations by L. Noss]
    - Comment by Emmy Westphal (née Ronnefeldt), undated
    - 11 Apr 1916
    - May 1917
    - June 1917
    - 6 Sept 1917
    - 16 Sept 1917
    - 14 Oct 1917
    - 27 Oct 1917
    - 14 Nov 1917
    - 28 Nov 1917
    - 9 Feb 1918
    - 15 Feb 1918
    - 21 Mar 1918
    - to Mrs. Ronnefeldt, 5 May 1918
    - to Emmy, 5 May 1918
    - 20 Aug 1918
    - 28 Sept 1918
    - Sept 1922
  - Annotated Extracts from selected letters in files of Schott/Mainz made on basis of Hindemith's conflict with the Nazi government re: Mathis der Maler opera, and his later association with AMP & Schott while in New Haven and Blonay, 1933-1960 (Box 19, Folder 327)
  - Correspondence between Kurt Stone and others re: Hindemith publications at AMP, 1955-1991 (Box 20, Folder 328)
  - Paul Hindemith personal Pocket Datebook entries while in USA, compiled by L. Noss from the original, on file in Paul Hindemith Institute, Frankfurt, May 1975 (Box 20, Folder 329)
    In longhand, with photocopy of two original pages 1937-1963. The last entries are from Gertrud Hindemith's datebook.
  - Typed copies and excerpts of Library of Congress holdings including correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 20, Folder 330)
    - Paul Hindemith-Paul Bekker, 25 Aug 1925
    - Paul Hindemith-Serge Koussevitzky (Paris), 1928
    - Paul Hindemith-O. Strunk, 12 Sept 1936 to 1 Mar 1937
    - Paul Hindemith-Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, 29 Apr 1937
    - Paul Hindemith-Paul Pisk, 6 Oct 1944
    - Folder also includes list of manuscripts by Paul Hindemith in Library of Congress:
    - Four Songs on Old Texts
    - Hérodiade
    - Konzertmusik für Klavier, Blechbläser und Harfen, opus 49
    - Birthday Greeting for Mrs. Coolidge (Musica divina, a canon à tre)
    - a published copy of Flute Sonata with corrections by Paul Hindemith
  - Luther Noss File of Paul Hindemith Miscellany (Box 20, Folder 331)
    - Random notes for an interview on Paul Hindemith
    - Entries from L. Noss's daily journal re: Paul Hindemith & Gertrud Hindemith
    - Conclusion of talk: The Hindemith We Never Knew - given to The Club, 1974
    - David Weinland and the Harmonium [US Military Field Organ], 1980
    - A. Rubeli: Hindemith and Zurich, 1968 - notes and excerpts about teaching at University of Zurich
    - Paul Hindemith and Wells College, 1940
    - Furtwängler and the Nazis, in Die Musik 27, p.437, 1935
    - M. Steinberg: notes for recording of Third String Quartet
    - Yale Daily News announcements, 28 Mar & 1 May 1940
    - Hindemithiana - student recollections, et. al. - much of this material is in other files
    - Misc. comments by:
    - Arthur Cohn: on Decca recording of opus 38 [Concerto for orchestra]
    - Lothar Klein. source?
    - George Lam. source?
    - Paul Hindemith's comments on Musicology, Salzburg, 21 Aug 1952
    - Paul Hindemith comment to Goddard Lieberson re: teaching
    - Paul Hindemith and The Club; three papers he read, 1946-1953
    - Rudolph Hindemith's wife, Maria Landes-Hindemith in Munich
    - Photo and biography in Neue Musik-Zeitung Stuttgart 43. Jahrgang, Heft 20 (s.329) with translation, 1922
    - List of premieres conducted by Paul Hindemith - in longhand
    - Table of residences, 1937-1963
  - National Music Council Bicentennial Plaque, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 332)
    - Text of inscription
    - Obituary of Mrs. Curtis, granddaughter of Horatio Parker
    - Memo from Merle Montgomery, president, National Music Council
    - New Haven Register notice, 12 Sept 1976
    - Memo from AMT (Anne-Marie Souliere?) re: ceremony
    - Letters: L. Noss-R. L. Ross
    - 2-color photo of ceremony with P. Nelson + article in New Haven Register, 16 September 1976
  - Hindemith Collection Curator's Reports, 1972 & 1973 (Box 20, Folder 333)
- PHOTOGRAPHS & DRAWINGS, 1901-1986; Series VIII; 1' (2 boxes)
  Photographs of Paul and Gertrud Hindemith are arranged chronologically and cover the years 1931 to 1973. Besides many informal poses, there are official portraits of Paul Hindemith by the Yale University New Bureau, copies of all the Christmas cards drawn by Paul Hindemith, a number of his original drawings, and a catalogue of an exhibition of Hindemith's drawings held in 1986.
  Additional photographs and photocards may be found in the Personal Correspondence, Series IX/Folders 339-355. The Easter Eggs Hindemith painted for Ralph Kirkpatrick are in Box 34. The 14 paintings on butcher paper which Hindemith created for Carl Lohmann's 25 anniversary celebration at Yale are found in Boxes 36-42. The window shade painted for the farewell party in 1953 is housed in Box 35.
  - Photographs & Drawings (Box 20, Folder 334)
    - Copy of Paul Hindemith at 6 yrs, given to K. Bauer (see p.4, Zeugnis in Bildern), 1901
    - Photocopy of photo of 12 people at Donaueschingen festival (see Folder 332), 1925
    - Rehearsal for Brahmsfest in Vienna (2 sizes) with A. Schnabel, B. Hubermann, P. Casals + plus print of same in Stereo Review 9 Sept 1972, 1933
    - Portrait by Geiringer/Horovitz, Vienna, 1933
    - Paul Hindemith with pen in right hand, holding quarto manuscript in left hand; no date, no place, 1939-40
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith; no date, no place, 1939-40
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith at lunch with Alfi, Bluch, Switzerland, 1940
    - Residence 134 West Elm St, New Haven CT, from Sept until Oct 1945, 1940
    - Paul Hindemith with Mr & Mrs Hugo Kortschak, Katherine Frazier at Cummington (MA) School - 2 copies, 27 Aug 1940
    - Paul Hindemith playing pochette on back steps of 134 West Elm St. (see Zeugnis in Bildern, p. 68), 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith & curator looking at paintings in Kunstgewerbe Museum, Vienna 1950, 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith at front door of Sprague Hall - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith on steps of Sprague Hall (I) - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Student party photos in spring 1943, West Elm St. house - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith on steps of Sprague Hall (II) - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith at student party with A. Etler, M. Kirschbaum - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Paul Hindemith in classroom with S. Q. Tam and R. Vinitsky - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
    - Other students without Paul Hindemith - copy of snapshot by Jean Moran, 1942-43
  - Photographs & Drawings (Box 20, Folder 335)
    - 2 drawings by Paul Hindemith sent to J. Moran, mid-1940s
    - Paul Hindemith seated in garden of 134 West Elm St., with shirtsleeves rolled up, by J. Dunlap, 1945
    - Residence 137 Alden Avenue, New Haven CT October 1945 until resignation
    - Collegium rehearsal of instrumentalists, 1946
    - Paul Hindemith at front door to Sprague Hall, 1946
    - Collegium rehearsals in Hendrie Hall, 1947
    - Paul Hindemith & Leonard Berkowitz in class, 1948
    - Garden Party for composition/theory students in May, at 137 Alden Ave, 1948
    - 10 pages of photocopies of photos from 1964 exhibit by ?, 1948
    - Commencement procession in June, 1948
    - Paul Hindemith in classroom with blackboard behind him, by B. Quashen, ca. 1948
    - Paul Hindemith in class, by B. Quashen, 1948-49
    - Original color photos by B. Quashen, 1948+
    - Paul Hindemith in front of Sprague Hall, by M. Barker Nelson (these are copies), 1949
    - Official photos of Yale University News Bureau, May 1949
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith celebrating 25th wedding anniversary in New York - May, 1949
    - Page of photocopy photos including 25th wedding anniversary in New York - May, Paul Hindemith conducting, Gertrud & Paul Hindemith together - property of John T Lowe + 1925; photo of 12 people at Donaueschingen festival, 1949
    - Paul Hindemith teaching in Salzburg, summer 1949
  - Photographs & Drawings (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith in the Garden, 137 Alden Avenue; one original sent to R & B. Simonds in December, 1948
    - 10 photos (photocopies) of Paul Hindemith, Gertrud & Paul Hindemith at home, in class. etc., 1948
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith in the garden, 137 Alden Avenue, 1950s?
    - Collegium rehearsal at the Cloisters, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, 1951
    - February party for Carl Lohmann: 13 photos of drawings by Paul Hindemith, autograph drawing of Lohman sent to F. W. Bronson with quote of 4 meas. from "Cal, the lad of Ohio's Anniversary Song" (see Folder 436 for complete melody and text and Boxes 36-42 - 14 tempera drawings on butcher paper), 1951
    - Official photos of Yale University News Bureau, by Alburtus, 1952
    - Paul Hindemith with finger in the air, by Gustav Schikola, Vienna, 1952
    - Paul Hindemith in the Stecherei/engraving studio at B. Schott's Söhne, Mainz, 1952
    - Paul Hindemith & students in class: J. Crawford, S. di Bonaventura, D. Loach, Y. Wyner, 1953
    - Prof. Ernst Reuter, mayor of Berlin, visits Paul Hindemith's classes and campus in the spring, 1953
    - 2 May - Farewell party - murals, etc. in 137 Alden Avenue (see also Box 35 - window shade), 1953
    - Paul Hindemith & Wieland Wagner in Bayreuth, summer, 1953
    - Paul Hindemith portrait by Gebauer, Bayreuth, 1953
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith in South America, autumn, 1953
    - Paul Hindemith in rehearsal, South America, autumn, 1953
    - Paul Hindemith in full dress, South America, autumn, 1953
  - Photographs & Drawings (Box 20, Folder 337)
    - Piper's Kunstkalendar: charcoal drawing (reproduction) by Münch, done perhaps the year before, 1954
    - Paul Hindemith conducting Vienna Philharmonic in Tokyo; sent to O. Cox, 1956
    - Photo by Jutta Vialon, Bremen; sent to O & L. Noss in December, 1956
    - Paul Hindemith conducting orchestral rehearsal in Munich (see Zeugnis in Bildern, p. 83), 1958
    - Paul Hindemith-L & O. Cox Thank you card, Feb 1959
    - Photo by Presse-Foto Röhnert, Berlin, 18 Feb 1959
    - Photo by Coleman & Clinton, New Haven, in Master's House, Silliman College, of secret visit to New Haven, 18 February 1959
    - Stevenson cartoon in New Yorker magazine - negative: "Heavens, Loretta, just because you don't care for Hindemith, doesn't mean there's payola involved!", 1959
    - Paul Hindemith near villa in Blonay, sent to R. Donovans, late 1950s?
    - Rehearsal for Collegium concert 19 Feb; contact sheets and prints; large photo by Ernesto V. Epistola taken during rehearsal, 1960
    - Negative of inscribed photo given to Yale Music Library when Paul Hindemith was here: To our faithful old Music School Library, the playground and nursery for composers and theorists. Paul Hindemith, Feb 1960
    - Paul and Gertrud Hindemith embarking on the SS United States for Le Havre on 12 Mar, sent by Gertrud Hindemith to the Donovans, 1960
    - Photos from Sion, Switzerland near Blonay by L. Noss. Prints made from slides in 1973: Paul Hindemith, Gertrud Hindemith, O. Noss, L. Noss, 30 July 1960
    - Photos of lunch at Poste et Paiz Hotel, Sion, Switzlerland: Paul Hindemith, Gertrud Hindemith, O. Noss, L. Noss, Prof & Mrs Heinrich Straumann, Zurich, 1960
    - Paul Hindemith in the garden, Blonay(?), sent to O. Cox for Christmas, undated, 1961?
    - Commemoration reception with index of people, at Yale, 7 Nov 1964
    - Exhibit in Beinecke Library in conjuction with Commemoration (see item above), 7 Nov 1964
    - Postcard reproduction of oil portrait of Paul Hindemith by P. Gartmann, appeared on month of May 1965 calendar, sent to O & L. Noss by Gertrud Hindemith in December, 1964
    - Photo by Kurt Pfefferle, Frankfurt, of Paul Hindemith conducting, sent to R & B. Simonds 1964, sent to O & L. Noss 1965
    - Photo by Kurt Pfefferle, Frankfurt, sent to G & R. Donovan in January, 1965
    - Graves of Paul Hindemith & Gertrud Hindemith, Blonay, Switzerland, by L. Noss, 16 June 1973
    - Villa "La Chance," Blonay, siège de la Fondation Hindemith, card from H & H. Boatwright to L. Noss, 1977
    - Undated Miscellaneous Drawings and Notes, 1977
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-Grumman "Rocky Top" card with pencil drawing, 1977
    - 4 placecards for R & B. Simonds, 1977
    - Thank you card to K. Bauer for Heidsieck champagne, 1977
    - Pencil drawing - Acceptance of Hallowelen invitation from Grummans, 1977
    - 3 folded drawings: Walt Whitman, Miss O'Meara, Egyptian figure with kythara in colored pencil, all initialed Paul Hindemith to W. T. Brown, 1977
    - Castelnuovo [-Tedesco] written in 11 languages during rehearsal of Castelnuovo-Tedesco's Concerto? 7 Dec 1940, 1977
    - Ink drawing of bugs, after P. Klee, 1977
    - 2 pencil drawings (Maschinenmorgen & Familie mit Masern im Mai) after P. Klee, 1977
    - Cover of Paul Reboux: Choucoune (minibook) with flying bugs in ink added by Paul Hindemith, 1977
    - Paul Hindemith - Der Komponist als Zeichner, exhibition catalogue of drawings, 1986
    - Musical game of 9 fragments to be assembled in the best sequence for which a prize was given; from J. Moran Myer; set of original manuscript in Paul Hindemith's hand from H. Fromm(?), 1986
- PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1927-1966; Series IX; 1' (3 boxes)
  Correspondence in Boxes 21-23, Folders 338-356, is with personal friends, colleagues, students, and Paul Hindemith's lawyer, Oscar Cox. The bulk of letters dates from 1937 to 1966. Business letters between Hindemith and his publishers are found in Boxes 15-17, Folders 282-299, while letters pertaining to his professional life are found in Box 19, Folder 326.
  This series also contains a number of photocards; i.e., postcards bearing a photo of Paul Hindemith or Gertrud & Paul Hindemith, many of which are not included in Series VIII, Photographs & Drawings. The photocards emanate from Salzburg, New York, Vienna, Bayreuth, Munich, and Hamburg.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1927-1940 (Box 21, Folder 338)
    - Paul Hindemith-Maurits Frank, from Paul Hindemith Briefe, ed. Dieter Rexroth, 12 Apr 1927
    - Paul Hindemith-Gerhard Maass autograph letter signed/German, 27 May 1929
    - Paul Hindemith-Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge typed letter signed/German photocopy, 8 May 1930
    - Gertrud & Paul Hindemith-Lydia Hoffman Behrendt autograph letter signed/German photocopy, late Apr 1936
    - Paul Hindemith-E. S. Coolidge autograph letter signed/German photocopy, 29 Apr 1937
    - Paul Hindemith-Ernest Voigt/AMP autograph letter signed/German, 2 Apr 1938
    - Paul Hindemith-Dr. Gahlenstein autograph letter signed/German, 25 Jan 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-L. Hoffmann-Behrendt autograph letter signed/German photocopy, 8 Feb 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, Apr 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 3 May 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 4 May 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 27 Jul 1939
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 21 Feb 1940
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 24 Feb 1940
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, Mar 1940
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 4 Mar 1940
    - Paul Hindemith-Aaron Copland autograph letter signed/English photocopy, 4 Mar 1940
    - Paul Hindemith-G. Mackenzie autograph letter signed/English, 15 Mar 1940